## Joshua Martínez

Website: https://mynjj.github.io

### Profile

Hardworking passionate profesional, currently studying a Msc. in Computer Science. With experience in software development, which taught me to translate my hard-skills to useful products. Highly responsible on my work. Excited to learn more, try new things, face challenges, and to help.

### **EDUCATION**

IT University  Master of Science in Computer Science	Copenhaguen, Denmark  Aug. 2020 – Present
• Universidad La Salle • Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Communications; GPA: 4 (9.76/10.0)	Mexico City, Mexico Aug. 2012 – Nov. 2016
• Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México Bachelor of Mathematics	Mexico City, Mexico Aug. 2014 – Jul. 2018
Experience	
TIDE Software Engineer	Mexico City, Mexico Jan. 2019 - Aug. 2020

I developed many useful skills, learned to deliver fully functional products and to take responsability for them as a team. Designed and implemented creative solutions with several technologies.

- Employee time clock: Raspberry Pi's with multiple identification and synchronization features. Integrated sensors SDK's (C/Java), implemented features for the main service (Node.js), and UI(React)
- Airport Lounge app: Android/iOS app with React Native. Several features, integrated to an existing backend and created a backend-for-frontend for other features (Node.js/sails.js). Other technologies used: Redux, Firebase FCM
- o **Scotiabank's online pride parade**: Basic MMORPG for 2020's stay@home Pride Parade. AWS/EC2 instances running a Phaser.js game, connecting to WebSocket servers (Typescript). Redis used for chat features.
- IOT devices monitor: Utilities to provide software updates, remote SSH access and stats recopilation for remote technical support. Implemented features on both sides (Node.js, PHP/Symfony, React, Linux scripting).
- Coca-cola promotional game: Soccer game for marketing stands of Coca-cola running on Raspberry Pi's, controlled by a Wii controller. Created with Python/Pygame.
- Airport Lounge software: Software spanning several company areas. Implemented several features, on both backend (PHP/Symfony) and frontend (React/Redux).
- Restaurant software: Highly customized restaurant software. Implemented several features, on both backend (PHP/Symfony) and frontend (React/Redux).

### VtSoftware

Software Engineer

Playa del Carmen, Mexico Jun. 2017 - May 2018

Email: djoshuamartinezpineda@gmail.com

I learned how to translate my academic knowledge to useful software. One of the most important skills I learned is to listen to the client requirements and design accordingly.

- Vacation Clubs Payroll Software: Modeled and designed according to customer needs. Bootstraped project on PHP/Laravel and Vue.js, integrated to an existing sales system DB.
- **Hotel Inventory Software**: Modeled and designed according to customer needs. Bootstraped project on PHP/Laravel and jQuery.

# École de Technologie Supérieure

 $Research\ Internship$ 

Montreal, Canada Apr. 2015 - Jul. 2015

• Estimation of disparity on GPUs: Research on disparity estimation algorithms and implementation on Matlab and then using C/CUDA

## OTHER EXPERIENCE

• Teaching activities: Private tutor on mathematics and programming, mostly focusing on kids (from 9 to 16). Social Service as an English teacher for adults.

# ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES

- ANFEI's award: Highest GPA on engineering faculty. Graduated with Magna Cum Laude.
  Robotics Winter School. 2013: INAOE, Puebla, Mexico.
  Robotics competitions. 2011 2013: Participation on Robocup competitions with the school robotics team. Istanbul, Turkey and Mexico City.

  • Programming competitions.: IEEExtreme Programming competitions.

## SKILLS I'VE WORKED WITH

Languages	Technologies
JS, TS, Node, Python, Matlab, C, Java, SQL, PHP	• Web frontend:: React, Redux, React Native, Vue.js, Phaser. Raspberry Pi, Vuejs, Laravel, Symfony, Linux, Sails-js, Redis, AWS, Echarts, Socket-io